PRITHVI KISHAN

prithvi.kishan1665@gmail.com prithvikishan.github.io inkedin.com/in/prithvi-kishan github.com/PrithviKishan

I am a Pre-final year Engineering student well versed in both Electronics and Computer Science fields. Looking forward to utilizing and improving my expertise with every organization I work with to develop better technologies.

EDUCATION

07/2018 - 07/2022

B.E, Electronics and Telecommunication Engineering,

BMS Institute of Technology & Management

Bangalore, India

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

01/2021 - 06/2021

MATLAB developer intern, MATLAB helper

Remote

- Developed MATLAB projects and produced technical work on topics including Twitter Analysis, Face Recognition using MATLAB mobile.
- Assisted clients with 1 on 1 in projects and research work.

02/2020 - 05/2020

Campus Ambassador, Delhi Technical University

Remote

 Represented and advertised TATVA, the Annual Techno-Management Fest organized by the Department of Applied Chemistry, DTU, and enrolled over 300+ participants.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

MATLAB

Python

• C

Version Control

- MS Office
- Video production
- eo CSS

PROJECTS

Gesture Controlled Speech synthesizer for the deaf and mute

08/2020 - 12/2020

- Developed a glove capable of gesture detection using flex sensors connected to an Arduino along with a Bluetooth module.
- 2nd place in Project-Based learning competition held at BMSIT,04/2021.

IPL statistics visualizer

 Helped non-cricket followers to understand cricket statistics and numbers intuitively with the help of graphs and charts in MATLAB. Techniques used were Regex and Web scraping.

Face-Recognition program

09/2020 - 10/2020

• Deployed the AlexNet CNN to train a transfer learning model to recognize people's faces captured using a webcam in MATLAB and achieved an accuracy of 94% on a test dataset.

Automatic song generator

11/2020 - 01/2021

- Developed a program to reference lyrics from the Genius.com API and automatically generate songs in python.
- Techniques used: Web-scraping, Markov graph, Text-to-speech, and audio layering.